<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Blog</title><link>https://debdut.blog/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2025 Debdut Chakraborty</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 22:51:56 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://debdut.blog/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fundamental Theory of Arithmetic</title><link>https://debdut.blog/2024/03/fundamental-theory-of-arithmetic/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 22:51:56 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://debdut.blog/2024/03/fundamental-theory-of-arithmetic/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is one and only one unique prime factorization of a number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a number, like \(34\), factoring it we get -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$
\begin{align}
fact(34) = 2 * 17
\end{align}
$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Question is, can you have a different set that is other than { \(2\) } It may seem evident from the example above but let’s start with an informal proof.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, we&amp;rsquo;ll use a different definition of a set, where elements &lt;strong&gt;can show up multiple times&lt;/strong&gt; - this is critical in making the proof simpler.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Perpetual Rocket.Chat Develop Deployment</title><link>https://debdut.blog/2022/06/perpetual-rocket.chat-develop-deployment/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 18:49:18 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://debdut.blog/2022/06/perpetual-rocket.chat-develop-deployment/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Since joining Rocket.Chat last year I&amp;rsquo;ve been having to deploy it uncountable times, multiple times in a single day even. One of the most critical things, is needing to check community issues on &lt;em&gt;latest develop&lt;/em&gt; branch (to make sure it&amp;rsquo;s not already fixed) everytime before funneling to product. So it was a lot of re-deploying every few days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do have a &lt;code&gt;develop&lt;/code&gt; tagged docker image, but to &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; be on the latest develop I&amp;rsquo;d need to re-pull it every once in a while, and that doesn&amp;rsquo;t really help much.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Creating Shell Builtins</title><link>https://debdut.blog/2022/06/creating-shell-builtins/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 15:31:59 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://debdut.blog/2022/06/creating-shell-builtins/</guid><description>&lt;!--this is my personal draft written years ago--&gt;
&lt;h1 id="what-are-my-goals-for-this-article"&gt;What are my goals for this article?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before writing this, I was thinking about it from the reader&amp;rsquo;s point of view, and it came to my attention that the goal of this article might get misinterpreted. So this section is to make sure that doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen. My goal for this article, is very simple and straight forward. Following this, you&amp;rsquo;ll have a much better understanding of what shell &lt;code&gt;builtins&lt;/code&gt; are, and why you should use them instead of general commands, whenever you can. There is a section that shortly goes through the process of even creating one ourselves. But that should &lt;strong&gt;not be considered to be a tutorial&lt;/strong&gt;. This article won&amp;rsquo;t teach you how to create a built-ins yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>